Guide to the Robert Hammond Papers ca. 1949-1998 MSS.164
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series II: Manuscripts: Prose
  - Subseries II.A: Robert Hammond
    - Don't Call Me Ishmael (French, typed translation) (3 of 7), 1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Don't Call Me Ishmael (French, typed translation) (4 of 7), 1993 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Don't Call Me Ishmael (French, typed translation) (5 of 7), 1993 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Don't Call Me Ishmael (French, typed translation) (6 of 7), 1993 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Don't Call Me Ishmael (French, typed translation) (7 of 7), 1993 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Don't Call Me Ishmael (French, files on 13 3.5" diskettes), 1993 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Fernandel and Raimu as Informants (typed), undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Flora Tristan (handwritten & typed chapters) (see also Series 1A, box 2, folder 41), undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - French Film Scenarios (typed & published galleries), Oct 1958 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - History of the Polish Film [with Charles Ford] (ver. 1: typed) (1 of 2), undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - History of the Polish Film (ver. 1: typed) (2 of 2), undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - History of the Polish Film (ver. 2: typed with edits) (1 of 2), undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - History of the Polish Film (ver. 2: typed with edits) (2 of 2), undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - History of the Polish Film (ver. 3: typed, "Revised") (1 of 2), 1987 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - History of the Polish Film (ver. 3: typed, "Revised") (2 of 2), 1987 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Killed in the Egg (handwritten in notebooks) (see also Series 1A, box 1, folders 3 & 4), undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Mexican Film Scenarios (typed), 1958 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Nancy Blue and the Smuggler's Cave (handwritten & typed drafts), undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - The Queen's Love Story (ver. 1: typed), 1961 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - The Queen's Love Story (ver. 2: typed, French), undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Solitaire (handwritten in notebook) (see also Series 1A, box 5, folders 100-103), undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - That Austrian Bitch (ver. 1: assorted handwritten chapters), undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - That Austrian Bitch (ver. 2: assorted typed chapters) (see also Series 1A, box 5, folders 110-113), undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - La Violoncelle [with Michael Barjansky] (typed synopsis), undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - La Violoncelle (ver. 1: handwritten in notebooks) (1 of 3), undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - La Violoncelle (ver. 1: handwritten in notebooks) (2 of 3), undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - La Violoncelle (ver. 1: handwritten in notebooks) (3 of 3), undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - La Violoncelle (ver. 2: typed) (1 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - La Violoncelle (ver. 2: typed) (2 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - La Violoncelle (research notes & documents) (1 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - La Violoncelle (research notes & documents) (2 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Subseries II.B: Various Authors
    Prose written by various other authors.
    - Common Market Cousins - Waltz, Robin (typed) (1 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Common Market Cousins - Waltz, Robin (typed) (2 of 2) (see also Series 1A, box 2, folders 27 & 28), undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Portraits with Backgrounds - Barjansky, Catherine (photocopy of book), 1947 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - The Sculptress Queen - Barjansky, Catherine (typed), undated (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Subseries II.C: Unknown Authors
    Prose of unidentified authorship (presumably by Hammond). For manuscripts with no identifiable title, character names or other distinguishing labels are provided in quotation marks. Manuscripts are in English unless otherwise noted.
    - Bob sur un Banc a Broadway (typed, French) (Christian Lutz) (1 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Bob sur un Banc a Broadway (typed, French) (Christian Lutz) (2 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - The Truth (typed), undated (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Untitled Journal Article: "American actors in France" (typed) (Charles Ford), undated (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Untitled Prose (handwritten), undated (Box 8, Folder 43)
- Series III: Interviews
  - Subseries III.A: Written interviews
    Written interviews conducted by Robert Hammond
    - Cocteau Reflects for Me, I Reflect for Him (microfiche), 1984 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Eric Rohmer Talks about Film Scripts (handwritten & typed), undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - An Interview with Bunuel's Scenarist: Jean-Claude Carriere (typed), undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Interview with Charles Spaak (handwritten in notebook), 1957 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - The King of Hearts and Daniel Boulanger: An Interview (typed), undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Subseries III.B: Audio interviews
    This subseries consists of 28 audiocassettes of interviews conducted by Robert Hammond. There are in two boxes (12 and 13), and are listed here using the labels written on each cassette by Hammond – the cassettes have not been played to confirm their content.
    Conditions Governing Access
    Audio interviews have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
    - Side 1: Alekan (July 1971) side 2: blank Brand/Length (min): Sony-C/90 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Side 1: Auclair side 2: blank Brand/Length (min): NA, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Side 1: Michael Auclair (7/23) side 2: blank Brand/Length (min): 3M-C/60, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Side 1: Auric side 2: blank Brand/Length (min): Sony-C/90, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Side 1: Lucille Costa (Minouche) side 2: blank Brand/Length (min): Sonocolor -6/60, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Side 1: Lucille Costa (Minouche) side 2: blank Brand/Length (min): NA, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Side 1: Marie Dea side 2: Marie Dea Brand/Length (min): NA, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Side 1: Marie Dea (July 6) side 2: Marie Dea (July 6) Brand/Length (min): 3M-C/60, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Side 1: Delannoy side 2: Delannoy Brand/Length (min): Universal/60, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Side 1: Delannoy side 2: blank Brand/Length (min): Scotch-C/90, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Side 1: Jean Delannoy side 2: blank Brand/Length (min): NA, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Side 1: Dermit side 2: Dermit (good for this side only), undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Side 1: Dermit side 2: Dermit Brand/Length (min): NA, undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Side 1: Dermit side 2: Dermit Brand/Length (min): RCA-CV/60, undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Side 1: Langlois side 2: blank Brand/Length (min): Sony-C/90, undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Side 1: Jean Marais side 2: Jean Marais Brand/Length (min): NA, undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Side 1: Jean Marais (train) side 2: Jean Marais (restaurant), undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Side 1: Lee Miller side 2: blank Brand/Length (min): Agfa-C/90, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Side 1: Lee Miller (w/ M. Hammond, Penrose & 1st wife) side 2: NA, undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Side 1: Louis Page side 2: Louis Page Brand/Length (min): Sony-C/90, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Side 1: Perier side 2: Misc. sound from Orphee, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Side 1: Perier side 2: blank Brand/Length (min): RCA-CV/60, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Side 1: Pinoteau (restaurant) side 2: Pinoteau (restaurant) Brand/Length (min): Scotch-C/90, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Side 1: Pinoteau I side 2: Pinoteau II Brand/Length (min): Scotch-C/60, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Side 1: Nicole Stephane side 2: Michel Auclair Brand/Length (min): Scotch/60, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Side 1: Nicole Stephane side 2: blank Brand/Length (min): Sony-HF/90, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Side 1: Tiquet side 2: blank Brand/Length (min): Sony-C/90, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Side 1: Mme Weissweler side 2: blank Brand/Length (min): Agfa-C/90, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Series IV: Miscellaneous
  - Subseries IV.A: French cinema publications
    French cinema publications featuring screenplays and directors.
    - L'Avant Scene Cinema #361: Hommage a Roberto Rossellini, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Collection 24 souvenirs/seconde: Jean Delannoy, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Jean Dreville: 40 ans de cinema, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Le Monde Illustre #28: Les Dernieres Vacances, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Paris Theatre #18: Un Revenant / Les Amoureux sont Seuls au Monde, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Paris Theatre #25: Bolero / Liberte Provisoire, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Paris Theatre #30: Aux Yeux du Sovenir / Au Royaume des Cieux, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Subseries IV.B: French cinema promotional materials
    French cinema promotional booklets and flyers.
    - Film Festival Flyers: Marguerite Duras & Charles Spaak, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Les Honneurs de la Guerre (promotional booklet), undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Le Lien de Parente (promotional flyer), undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Les Nuits de la Pleine Lune (promotional booklet), undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - O de conduite (promotional flyer), undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - La Triche (promotional booklet), undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Subseries IV.C: Various media and database printouts
    Diskettes containing various correspondence, audio reels and three "green-bar" format database printouts of the Hammond Film Script Archive (not current). The diskettes and audio tapes are listed here using the labels written by Hammond – their content has not been otherwise confirmed.
    - Correspondence I: work (5.25" diskette with directory printout), 1980-1994 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence II: work (5.25" diskette with directory printout), 1980-1995 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Hammond Bio for M.L. (5.25" diskette), undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence with Charles & Xiapoing: Mode I (5.25" diskette), 1989-? (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence with Charles & Xiapoing: Mode II (5.25" diskette), undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Projects (5.25" diskette with directory printout), 1996 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - General Correspondence (5.25" diskette), 1997 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Charlie Corresp. (5.25" diskette), 1997 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: work (5.25" diskette), 1998 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: work (5.25" diskette), 1998 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Joe South / The Band (0.25" audio reel), undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Lucy in the Sky with Diamonds "for playing with Tues in Autumn" (0.25" audio reel), undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Frosh (0.25" audio reel), undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Mostly Frosh (0.25" audio reel), undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Juniors I (0.25" audio reel), undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Mrs. Body (0.25" audio reel), undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Hammond Filmscript Bibliographies (ver. 1: bound), 1983 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Hammond Filmscript Bibliographies (ver. 2: legal), 1983 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Hammond Filmscript Bibliographies (ver. 3: legal), 1984 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Series V: Correspondence
  Correspondence Robert Hammond received from various professional and personal acquaintances. The number of letters in each folder is indicated as (##).
  - Barjansky - King Bourouin (7), 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Don't Call Me Ishmael - NYU Press (5), 1995-1996 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Michele Duflos (8), 1976-1978 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Florence Gould Foundation (grant proposal) (6), 1997 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Gunilla & Oscar Haac (14), 1995-1997 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Margaret Harrison (O'Flaherty) (9), 1959-1961 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Margaret Harrison (O'Flaherty) (13), 1951-1962 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Margaret Harrison (O'Flaherty) (12), 1962-1980 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Margaret Harrison (O'Flaherty) (poems and photos), undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Susie Lavier (French) (15), 1949-1951 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Susie Lavier (French) (9), 1952-1956 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Susie Lavier (French) (6), 1957-1957 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Susie Lavier (French) (13), 1957-1957 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Susie Lavier (French) (7), 1958 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Susie Lavier (French) (14), 1959-1965 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Susie Lavier (French) (14), 1967-1969 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Susie Lavier (French) (13), 1970-1976 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Susie Lavier (French) (14), 1979-1991 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Susie Lavier (French) (16), undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Susie Lavier (photos from correspondence), 1957-1957 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Lucie O'Brien (7), January, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Lucie O'Brien (12), February, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Lucie O'Brien (16), March, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Lucie O'Brien (12), April, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Lucie O'Brien (17), May, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Lucie O'Brien (7), June, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Lucie O'Brien (12), September, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Lucie O'Brien (11), October, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Lucie O'Brien (16), November, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Lucie O'Brien (11), December, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Lucie O'Brien (10), January, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Lucie O'Brien (11), February, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Lucie O'Brien (12), March, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Lucie O'Brien (19), April-June, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Lucie O'Brien (12), September-October, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Lucie O'Brien (11), November-December, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Lucie O'Brien (15), January-February, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Lucie O'Brien (14), March-April, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Lucie O'Brien (15), May-June, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Lucie O'Brien (8), 1969 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Lucie O'Brien (9), 1970-1978 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Lucie O'Brien (photos & ephemera), undated (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Dominique Ottenwaelter (French) (14), 1978 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Dominique Ottenwaelter (French) (15), 1979 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Dominique Ottenwaelter (French) (15), 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Dominique Ottenwaelter (French) (15), 1982 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Dominique Ottenwaelter (French) (13), 1983 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Dominique Ottenwaelter (French) (25), 1984 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Dominique Ottenwaelter (French) (17), 1985-1987 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Pascal Vrebos (French & English) (18), 1978-1982 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Unidentifiable Correspondence (French & English) (7), 1950-1968 (Box 10, Folder 51)
- Series VI: Production Photos
  Series VI contains original production photos (along with photocopies) of three French films. The number of photos in each folder is indicated as (##).
  - La Belle et la Bete (9), undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - La Belle et la Bete (photocopies) (25), undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - L'Eternel Retour (7), undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - L'Eternel Retour (photocopies) (7), undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Orphee (40) (1 of 2), undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Orphee (41) (2 of 2), undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Orphee (photocopies) (21), undated (Box 13, Folder 7)